# SAMINKA KATUWAWALA

# DATA ANALYST

## **CONTACT**

Lamprey Street Menifee, California, 92586 805.264.3266 schamathk@gmail.com saminkak.github.io

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S. POLITICAL
SCIENCE/DATA ANALYTICS •
MARCH 2024
UC San Diego
San Diego, CA
Provost Honors

GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS
CERTIFICATION • AUGUST 2024

## **KEY SKILLS**

SQL R Python Excel Machine Learning Models Data Exploration Data Visualization Communication Strategic Thinking

# **PROJECTS**

Data Exploration using SQL Server Visualizations in Tableau Data Cleaning in SQL Server Exploring Correlation with Python Housing Correlation with Python Naïve Bayes Model in R Analyzing Correlation in R

#### **PROFILE**

Analytical, quick-thinking and creative data analyst with hands on experience in data exploration and data cleaning using R, SQL, Python and Excel. Knowledge in analyzing and implementing policies and guidelines. Knowledge on how to create useful visualizations using Tableau and presentations in Excel. Experience using machine learning models to make predictions on larger datasets.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

WILDFIRE PREDICTION PROJECT • JUNE 2023 - AUGUST 2023

UC San Diego • San Diego, California

This project was part of the AlertCalifornia project that is in place as early warning system for wildfires in rural areas. Our project consisted of collection, calculating and analyzing multiple data points in an attempt to use the camera system of AlertCalifornia to predict the likely hood of a wildfire in any given area. I was in charge of calculating the soil moisture content using rain levels and ambient temperature as well as using the data to analyze the type of foliage that would be present in a certain area.

PRODUCT MANAGER • OCTOBER 2020 - JANUARY 2023

SKS Market • San Diego, California

Product manager for an online business. I was in charge of researching potential products, analyzing samples for quality and managing logistics for products sold through the business. I was able to understand how to constantly adapt to an ever-changing environment and have a deeper understand of what clients are looking for with the products that were sold.

BANKER • JANUARY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2020

Wells Fargo Bank • San Diego, California

Started as a teller and was later promoted to a banker. I understood how to correctly analyze customers' needs to match them with products that will benefit them. I also had experience in understanding the needs of a business as I was being trained to be the business banker for my branch. I was exposed to managerial duties as I was the stand-in manager when managers were not present.